Applied and decorative arts photograph collection (medals-musical instruments).
Yale University Arts Library
Applied and decorative arts photograph collection (armor-manuscripts).
1900-2005
VRC 6.1
Yale University Arts Library
41.6
100 boxes (Boxes 1-100 of 172)
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of applied and decorative arts, predominantly European and American. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by medium. Principal categories include ceramics, furniture, glass, illuminated manuscripts, and silverware. Further arranged by chronological period, country, or region. Individual artists listed, if known.
Scope and Contents
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of applied and decorative arts, predominantly European and American. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Decorative arts; Photographs; Reproductions
- Armor and Weapons. (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous works., 25 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
  - Arabia., 1 (Box 1)
  - Persia., 3 (Box 1)
  - Roman., 1 (Box 1)
  - France., 7 (Box 1)
  - Germany., 50 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous works and pre-XVI C., 8 (Box 2)
    - XVI Century., 34 (Box 2)
    - XVII Century., 8 (Box 2)
  - Italy., 19 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 3)
    - XIV Century., 1 (Box 3)
    - XV Century., 2 (Box 3)
    - XVI Century., 15 (Box 3)
  - Spain., 2 (Box 3)
    Includes two folders of miscellaneous clippings.
- Basketry. (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 3)
- Bookbinding. (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous works., 2 (Box 3)
  - Persia., 3 (Box 3)
  - England., 3 (Box 3)
  - Flanders., 1 (Box 3)
  - France., 13 (Box 3)
  - Germany., 2 (Box 3)
- Ceramics. (Box 4)
  - Islamic., 63 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous works., 2 (Box 4)
    - Persia., 55 (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous works., 6 (Box 4)
      - IX Century., 4 (Box 4)
      - X Century., 4 (Box 4)
      - XI Century., 1 (Box 4)
      - XII Century., 13 (Box 4)
      - XIII Century., 15 (Box 4)
      - XIV Century., 4 (Box 4)
      - XVI Century., 7 (Box 5)
      - XVII Century., 1 (Box 5)
    - Turkey., 6 (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 5)
      - XVI Century., 4 (Box 5)
      - XVIII Century., 1 (Box 5)
  - Ancient World., 324 (Box 5)
    - Near East., 9 (Box 5)
    - Egypt., 3 (Box 5)
    - Aegean., 22 (Box 5)
      Includes a folder of photos of ceramics in the Y. U. A. G.
    - Greece., 281 (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous works., 9 (Box 6)
      - Geometric., 11 (Box 6)
      - Orientalizing., 8 (Box 6)
      - Corinthian., 23 (Box 6)
      - Black Figure., 74 (Box 7)
        - Miscellaneous works., 46 (Box 7)
        - Amasis Painter., 1 (Box 8)
        - Exekias., 12 (Box 8)
        - Lysippides Painter., 2 (Box 8)
        - Nikosthenes., 2 (Box 8)
        - Nikoxenos Painter., 1 (Box 8)
        - Phrynos., 2 (Box 8)
        - Psiax., 4 (Box 8)
        - Rycroft Painter., 2 (Box 8)
        - Xenokles Painter., 2 (Box 8)
      - Dimorphic., 3 (Box 8)
        - Andokides Painter., 3 (Box 8)
      - Red Figure., 130 (Box 9)
        - Miscellaneous works., 32 (Box 9)
        - Chicago Painter., 2 (Box 9)
        - Poygnotus., 1 (Box 9)
        - Providence Painter., 2 (Box 9)
        - Archaic period., 36 (Box 10)
          - Miscellaneous works., 5 (Box 10)
          - Berlin Painter., 4 (Box 10)
          - Brygos Painter., 6 (Box 10)
          - Epiktetos., 3 (Box 10)
          - Euphronios., 3 (Box 10)
          - Kleophrades Painter., 7 (Box 10)
          - Myson., 1 (Box 10)
          - Oltos., 3 (Box 10)
          - Phintias., 3 (Box 10)
          - Smikros., 1 (Box 10)
        - Classic period., 27 (Box 11)
          - Miscellaneous works., 8 (Box 11)
          - Duris., 5 (Box 11)
          - Hermonax., 2 (Box 11)
          - Kleophon Painter., 2 (Box 11)
          - Niobid Painter., 1 (Box 11)
          - Pan Painter., 4 (Box 11)
          - Penthesilea Painter., 3 (Box 11)
        - Late period., 30 (Box 11)
          - Miscellaneous works., 18 (Box 11)
          - Dinos Painter., 1 (Box 11)
          - Karneia Painter., 5 (Box 11)
          - Marsyas Painter., 3 (Box 11)
          - Meidias Painter., 2 (Box 11)
          - Pronomos Painter., 1 (Box 11)
      - White Ground., 19 (Box 12)
        - Miscellaneous works., 11 (Box 12)
        - Arkesilas Painter., 2 (Box 12)
        - Klio Painter., 1 (Box 12)
        - Achilles Painter., 5 (Box 12)
      - Hellenistic., 7 (Box 12)
    - Etruscan., 5 (Box 12)
    - Roman., 1 (Box 12)
    - Dura-Europas., 3 (Box 12)
  - Early Medieval., 3 (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous works., 3 (Box 12)
  - Renaissance to Modern., 326 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 13)
    - England., 135 (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous works., 10 (Box 13)
      - XVIII Century., 41 (Box 13)
      - XIX to XX Century., 86 (Box 14)
        - Miscellaneous works., 52 (Box 14)
        - Staffordshire., 28 (Box 14)
          - Miscellaneous works., 22 (Box 14)
          - Historical scenes., 6 (Box 14)
        - Wedgewood., 6 (Box 14)
    - France., 34 (Box 15)
      - Miscellaneous works., 5 (Box 15)
      - XVIII Century., 15 (Box 15)
      - XIX Century., 8 (Box 15)
      - XX Century., 6 (Box 15)
    - Germany., 30 (Box 15)
    - Holland., 3 (Box 15)
    - Italy., 60 (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous works., 9 (Box 16)
      - XV Century., 14 (Box 16)
      - XVI Century., 37 (Box 16)
    - Mexico., 2 (Box 16)
    - Russia., 8 (Box 16)
      - Chagall, Marc, 1887-1985., 8 (Box 16)
    - Spain., 5 (Box 17)
    - United States., 48 (Box 17)
      - Miscellaneous works., 9 (Box 17)
      - XIX Century., 20 (Box 17)
      - XX Century., 21 (Box 17)
        - Unknown and miscellaneous., 5 (Box 17)
        - Chihuly, Dale, 1941-., 1 (Box 17)
        - Cooper, Susie, 1902-., 2 (Box 17)
        - Cowan Pottery Studio., 1 (Box 17)
        - Frimkiss, Michael., 1 (Box 17)
        - Higby, Wayne, 1943-., 1 (Box 17)
        - Lakofsky, Charles L., 1922-., 1 (Box 17)
        - Lichtenstein, Roy, 1923-., 1 (Box 17)
        - Rockwood Pottery., 1 (Box 17)
        - Tiffany & Co., 2 (Box 17)
        - Voulkos, Peter, 1924-., 3 (Box 17)
        - Zeisel, Eva, 1906-., 2 (Box 17)
- Coins. (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous works., 4 (Box 18)
  - Greek., 29 (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous works., 7 (Box 18)
    - V Century., 7 (Box 18)
    - IV Century., 13 (Box 18)
    - III Century., 2 (Box 18)
  - Roman., 18 (Box 18)
  - Byzantine., 3 (Box 18)
  - England., 1 (Box 18)
  - Italy., 2 (Box 18)
  - United States., 1 (Box 18)
- Enamel. (Box 19)
  - Early Medieval., 15 (Box 19)
  - Romanesque to Modern., 83 (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous works., 4 (Box 19)
    - Flanders., 5 (Box 19)
    - France., 70 (Box 19)
      - XII Century., 15 (Box 19)
      - XIII Century., 15 (Box 19)
      - XV Century., 3 (Box 19)
      - XVI Century., 29 (Box 19)
      - XX Century., 8 (Box 20)
        - Goulden, Jean, 1878-1946., 8 (Box 20)
    - Germany., 4 (Box 20)
      - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 20)
      - XII Century., 3 (Box 20)
- Furniture. (Box 20)
  - Ancient World., 39 (Box 20)
    - Egypt., 10 (Box 20)
    - Greece., 1 (Box 20)
    - Roman., 28 (Box 20)
  - Romanesque to Modern., 1637 (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 21)
    - Austria., 12 (Box 21)
      - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 21)
      - XX Century., 11 (Box 21)
        - Coop Himmelblau., 2 (Box 21)
        - Hoffmann, Josef, 1870-1956., 4 (Box 21)
        - Moser, Kolo, 1868-1918., 3 (Box 21)
        - Wagner, Otto, 1841-1918., 2 (Box 21)
    - Belgium., 1 (Box 21)
      - XX Century., 1 (Box 21)
        - Horta, Victor, 1861-1947., 1 (Box 21)
    - Britain., 400 (Box 21)
      Includes three folders of miscellaneous clippings.
      - Miscellaneous works., 11 (Box 21)
      - Clocks., 25 (Box 21)
      - XVI Century., 19 (Box 21)
        - Miscellaneous works., 13 (Box 21)
        - Elizabethan (1558-1603)., 6 (Box 21)
      - XVII Century., 79 (Box 22)
        - Miscellaneous works., 5 (Box 22)
        - Jacobean (1603-1625)., 20 (Box 22)
        - Charles I., 2 (Box 22)
        - Charles II., 13 (Box 22)
        - Restoration., 11 (Box 22)
        - William and Mary (1689-1702)., 28 (Box 22)
      - XVIII Century., 223 (Box 23)
        - Miscellaneous works., 22 (Box 22)
        - Queen Anne (1702-1714)., 47 (Box 23)
        - Georgian (1714-1820)., 41 (Box 24)
        - Chippendale., 53 (Box 25)
        - Adam., 20 (Box 26)
        - Hepplewhite., 19 (Box 26)
        - Sheraton., 21 (Box 26)
      - XIX Century., 18 (Box 27)
        - Miscellaneous works., 12 (Box 27)
        - Burges, William, 1828-1881., 2 (Box 27)
        - Godwin, Edward William, 1833-1886., 2 (Box 27)
        - Hope, Thomas., 1 (Box 27)
        - Morris, William, 1834-1896., 1 (Box 27)
      - XX Century., 25 (Box 27)
        - Miscellaneous works., 7 (Box 27)
        - Mackintosh, Charles Rennie, 1868-1928., 17 (Box 27)
        - Voysey, C. F. A. 1857-1941., 1 (Box 27)
    - Denmark., 3 (Box 27)
    - Finland., 9 (Box 27)
      - XX Century., 9 (Box 27)
        - Aalto, Alvar, 1898-1976., 9 (Box 27)
    - Flanders., 5 (Box 27)
    - France., 224 (Box 28)
      - Miscellaneous works., 24 (Box 28)
      - Louis XIII., 1 (Box 28)
      - Louis XIV (1643-1715)., 22 (Box 28)
      - XVIII Century., 118 (Box 29)
        - Miscellaneous works., 13 (Box 29)
        - Regency (1715-1723)., 5 (Box 29)
        - Louis XV (1723-1750)., 60 (Box 29)
        - Louis XVI (1750-1793)., 40 (Box 30)
      - XIX to XX Century., 59 (Box 31)
        - Miscellaneous works., 12 (Box 31)
          - Unknown artists., 2 (Box 31)
          - Biennais., 1 (Box 31)
          - Dunand, Jacques, 1877-1942., 4 (Box 31)
          - Herbst, Rene., 1 (Box 31)
          - Jourdain, Francis., 1 (Box 31)
          - Le Corbusier, 1887-1965., 1 (Box 31)
          - Legrain, Pierre, 1889-1929., 1 (Box 31)
          - Sue, Louis, 1875-., 1 (Box 31)
        - Empire., 4 (Box 31)
        - Art Nouveau., 43 (Box 31)
          - Unknown artists., 2 (Box 31)
          - Charpentier, Alexandre, 1856-1909., 2 (Box 31)
          - Feure, Georges de, 1868-1943., 2 (Box 31)
          - Galle, Emil, 1846-1904., 6 (Box 31)
          - Guimard, Hector, 1867-1942., 9 (Box 31)
          - Majorelle, Louis, 1859-1926., 8 (Box 31)
          - Rousseau, Clement., 1 (Box 31)
          - Ruhlmann, Emile Jacques, 1877-1933., 12 (Box 31)
          - Sue et Mare., 1 (Box 31)
    - Germany., 40 (Box 32)
      - Miscellaneous works., 12 (Box 32)
      - XVIII Century., 14 (Box 32)
      - XIX to XX Century., 14 (Box 32)
        - Unknown artists., 2 (Box 32)
        - Known artists., 12 (Box 32)
          - Ernst, Max, 1891-1976., 2 (Box 32)
          - Keler, Peter., 1 (Box 32)
          - Klinckerfuss, Johannes, 1770-1831., 1 (Box 32)
          - Mies van der Rohe, 1886-1969., 5 (Box 32)
          - Olbrich, Joseph, 1876-1908., 1 (Box 32)
          - Riemerschmid, Richard., 1 (Box 32)
          - Thonet Firm., 1 (Box 32)
    - Holland., 9 (Box 32)
      - Miscellaneous works., 6 (Box 32)
      - XX Century., 3 (Box 32)
        - Rietveld, Gerrit, 1888-1964., 3 (Box 32)
    - Italy., 138 (Box 33)
      Includes two folders of miscellaneous clippings, one folder being devoted to the choirscreen, Church of S. Pietro, Perugia.
      - Miscellaneous works., 18 (Box 33)
      - XIV Century., 5 (Box 33)
      - XV Century., 20 (Box 33)
      - XVI Century., 47 (Box 34)
        - Miscellaneous works., 28 (Box 34)
        - Choir stalls., 19 (Box 34)
      - XVII Century., 17 (Box 35)
      - XVIII Century., 20 (Box 35)
      - XIX Century., 5 (Box 35)
      - XX Century., 6 (Box 35)
    - Norway., 7 (Box 36)
    - Portugal., 5 (Box 36)
    - Rumania., 1 (Box 36)
    - Spain., 32 (Box 36)
      - Miscellaneous works., 3 (Box 36)
      - XVI Century., 12 (Box 36)
      - XVII Century., 8 (Box 36)
      - XVIII Century., 6 (Box 36)
      - XIX to XX Century., 3 (Box 36)
        - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 36)
        - Gaudi, Antonio, 1852-1926., 2 (Box 36)
    - Sweden., 7 (Box 36)
    - Switzerland., 1 (Box 36)
    - Latin America., 12 (Box 36)
    - Canada., 2 (Box 36)
    - United States., 736 (Box 37)
      Includes four folders of miscellaneous clippings.
      - Miscellaneous works., 17 (Box 37)
      - Folk styles., 28 (Box 37)
        - Miscellaneous works., 5 (Box 37)
        - Ladderback., 12 (Box 37)
        - Pennsylvania German., 6 (Box 37)
        - Shaker., 4 (Box 37)
        - Windsor., 26 (Box 37)
      - XVII Century., 56 (Box 38)
        - Miscellaneous works., 18 (Box 38)
        - Chairs., 16 (Box 38)
        - Chests., 22 (Box 38)
      - William and Mary., 62 (Box 39)
        - Miscellaneous works., 24 (Box 39)
        - Chairs., 16 (Box 39)
        - Chests., 15 (Box 39)
        - Tables., 7 (Box 39)
      - Queen Anne., 88 (Box 40)
        - Miscellaneous works., 13 (Box 40)
        - Chairs., 44 (Box 40)
        - Chests., 16 (Box 40)
        - Tables., 15 (Box 40)
      - Chippendale., 207 (Box 41)
        - Miscellaneous works., 24 (Box 41)
        - Chairs., 70 (Box 41)
        - Chests., 36 (Box 42)
        - Tables., 31 (Box 42)
        - Known Artists., 46 (Box 43)
          - Miscellaneous artists., 15 (Box 43)
            - Badlam, Stephen, active 1791., 1 (Box 43)
            - Blin, Peter., 1 (Box 43)
            - Cogswell, John., 3 (Box 43)
            - Dennis, Thomas., 1 (Box 43)
            - Dunlap School of Cabinetmakers., 1 (Box 43)
            - Elliott, John., 1 (Box 43)
            - The Garvan Carver., 1 (Box 43)
            - Lemon, William, and McIntire, Samuel., 1 (Box 43)
            - Savery, William., 2 (Box 43)
            - Townsend, Edmund., 1 (Box 43)
            - Townsend, John., 1 (Box 43)
            - Tuffts, Thomas., 1 (Box 43)
          - Individual Artists., 31 (Box 43)
            - Affleck, Thomas., 5 (Box 43)
            - Chapin, Aaron and Eliphalet., 6 (Box 43)
            - Gillingham, James., 1 (Box 43)
            - Goddard-Townsend., 12 (Box 43)
            - James, Edward, -1798, and follower of., 4 (Box 43)
            - Randolph, Benjamin., 3 (Box 43)
      - Federal (Early Classic)., 116 (Box 44)
        - Miscellaneous works., 21 (Box 44)
        - Chairs., 29 (Box 44)
        - Secretaries., 5 (Box 44)
        - Sideboards., 12 (Box 45)
        - Tables., 19 (Box 45)
        - Known Artists., 30 (Box 45)
          - Miscellaneous Artists., 5 (Box 45)
            - Badlam, Stephen, and Skillin, Simeon., 2 (Box 45)
            - Phyfe, Duncan., 1 (Box 45)
            - Shaw, John., 1 (Box 45)
            - Willard, Aaron., 1 (Box 45)
          - Individual Artists., 25 (Box 45)
            - McIntire, Samuel, 1757-1811., 16 (Box 45)
              Many works done with William Lemon.
            - Seymour, John and Thomas, XVIII-XIX C., 9 (Box 45)
      - Empire (Late Classic)., 33 (Box 46)
        - Miscellaneous works., 19 (Box 46)
        - Known Artists., 14 (Box 46)
          - Lannuier, Charles Honore., 3 (Box 46)
          - Phyfe, Duncan., 11 (Box 46)
      - Victorian., 15 (Box 46)
        - Miscellaneous works., 4 (Box 46)
        - Known Artists., 11 (Box 46)
          - Belter, John Henry., 3 (Box 46)
          - Brooks, Thomas and Son., 1 (Box 46)
          - Brunswick-Balke-Collender Co., 1 (Box 46)
          - Hitchcock Chair Co., 1 (Box 46)
          - Meeks, John and Joseph., 1 (Box 46)
          - Roux, Alexander, 1813-1886., 3 (Box 46)
          - Wooton, William S., 1 (Box 46)
      - Miscellaneous XIX C., 17 (Box 46)
        - Unknown Artists., 7 (Box 46)
        - Known Artists., 10 (Box 46)
          - Corey, William., 1 (Box 46)
          - Edward, John., 1 (Box 46)
          - Furness, Frank, 1839-1912., 2 (Box 46)
          - Gragg, Samuel, active 1808-1812., 1 (Box 46)
          - Hoadley, Silas., 1 (Box 46)
          - Ordway, A. H. and Co.., 1 (Box 46)
          - Richardson, Henry Hobson, 1836-1886., 1 (Box 46)
          - Tisch, Charles., 1 (Box 46)
          - Wakefield Rattan Co., 1 (Box 46)
      - XX Century., 97 (Box 47)
        - Miscellaneous Artists., 59 (Box 47)
          - Unknown artists., 1 (Box 47)
          - Anderson and Bellah., 1 (Box 47)
          - Bayes, Jessie., 1 (Box 47)
          - Bertoia, Harry., 4 (Box 47)
          - Breuer, also Aalto and Mathsson., 1 (Box 47)
          - Castel, Wendell., 1 (Box 47)
          - Deskey, Donald, 1894-1989., 1 (Box 47)
          - Esherick, Wharton., 2 (Box 47)
          - Frankl, Paul T., 1887-1958., 1 (Box 47)
          - Gehry, Frank, 1929-., 4 (Box 47)
          - Gimson, Ernest W., 1 (Box 47)
          - Girard., 1 (Box 47)
          - Graves, Michael, 1934-., 2 (Box 47)
          - Greene, Charles and Henry., 4 (Box 47)
          - Henderson, William Penhallow., 1 (Box 47)
          - Herter Bros., 1 (Box 47)
          - Heywood Brothers and Wakefield Company., 1 (Box 47)
          - Hoffmann, Wolfgang., 1 (Box 47)
          - Horwitt, Nathan George., 1 (Box 47)
          - Jackson, Harry., 1 (Box 47)
          - James, Stewart., 1 (Box 47)
          - Knoll, Florence., 2 (Box 47)
          - Kuehne, Max., 3 (Box 47)
          - Loeser, Tom., 1 (Box 47)
          - Magistretti, Vico., 1 (Box 47)
          - Markwart, John., 1 (Box 47)
          - Mathews, Lucia Kleinhaus., 1 (Box 47)
          - Mathsson, Bruno., 1 (Box 47)
          - Mattia, Alphonse., 1 (Box 47)
          - Nakashima, George., 1 (Box 47)
          - Nicholson and Maier., 1 (Box 47)
          - Panton, Werner., 1 (Box 47)
          - Pascoe, Clifford., 2 (Box 47)
          - Prendergast, Charles, 1863-1934., 1 (Box 47)
          - Schoen, Eugene, 1880-1957., 1 (Box 47)
          - Stickley, Gustave, 1858-1942, and L. & J. G., 3 (Box 47)
          - Stonorov and Von Moltke., 2 (Box 47)
          - Meese and Baldwin., 1 (Box 47)
          - Venturi, Robert, 1925-., 2 (Box 47)
          - Wright, Russel., 1 (Box 47)
        - Individual Artists., 38 (Box 48)
          - Breuer, Marcel., 9 (Box 48)
          - Eames, Charles, 1901-1978., 5 (Box 48)
          - Saarinen, Eero., 12 (Box 48)
          - Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1867-1959., 12 (Box 48)
- Gems. (Box 49)
  - Ancient World., 16 (Box 49)
    - Greek., 10 (Box 49)
    - Roman., 6 (Box 49)
  - Byzantine and later., 12 (Box 49)
- Glass. (Box 50)
  See also: Stained Glass.
  - Islamic., 13 (Box 50)
  - Ancient World., 40 (Box 50)
    - Egypt., 5 (Box 50)
    - Roman., 35 (Box 50)
  - Early Medieval., 9 (Box 50)
  - Countries., 170 (Box 51)
    - Austria., 4 (Box 51)
    - Britain., 8 (Box 51)
      - Unknown Artists., 3 (Box 51)
      - Known Artists., 5 (Box 51)
        - Beilby, William, XVIII C., and family., 3 (Box 51)
        - Bone, Muirhead, 1876-., 1 (Box 51)
        - Dresser, Christopher, 1834-1904., 1 (Box 51)
    - France., 27 (Box 51)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 12 (Box 51)
        - Unknown Artists., 2 (Box 51)
        - Argy-Rousseau, G., XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 51)
        - Clichy Factory, XIX C., 1 (Box 51)
        - Daum, Auguste, 1854-1909, and Antonin., 4 (Box 51)
        - Lalique, Rene, 1860-1945., 2 (Box 51)
        - Massier, Clement, XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 51)
        - Matisse, Henri, 1869-1954., 1 (Box 51)
      - Individual Artists., 15 (Box 51)
        - Galle, Emile, 1846-1904., 15 (Box 51)
    - Germany., 12 (Box 51)
      - XVI Century., 5 (Box 51)
      - XVII Century., 5 (Box 51)
      - XX Century., 2 (Box 51)
        - Unknown Artists., 1 (Box 51)
        - Wagenfeld, Wilhelm., 1 (Box 51)
    - Holland., 4 (Box 51)
      - Unknown Artists., 1 (Box 51)
      - Copier, D. A., 1901-., 1 (Box 51)
      - Greenwood, Follower of, XIX C., 1 (Box 51)
      - Visscher, Anna Roemer, 1583-1651., 1 (Box 51)
    - Ireland., 3 (Box 51)
    - Italy., 16 (Box 51)
      - Miscellaneous works., 14 (Box 51)
      - XX Century., 2 (Box 51)
    - Norway., 1 (Box 51)
      - Palmquist, Sven, XX C., 1 (Box 51)
    - Russia., 1 (Box 51)
    - Sweden., 7 (Box 51)
      - Orrefors Glass, XX C., 7 (Box 51)
        - Miscellaneous works., 2 (Box 51)
        - Gate, Simon, XX C., 5 (Box 51)
    - United States., 97 (Box 52)
      - XVIII Century., 9 (Box 52)
        - Miscellaneous works., 5 (Box 52)
        - Amelung, New Bremen MD., 4 (Box 52)
      - XIX Century., 50 (Box 52)
        - Miscellaneous works., 35 (Box 52)
        - Known producers., 15 (Box 52)
          - Bakewell and Page., 2 (Box 52)
          - Sandwich Glass Co., 8 (Box 52)
          - Stiegel, H. W., Manheim PA., 5 (Box 52)
      - XX Century., 35 (Box 53)
        - Unknown Artists., 4 (Box 53)
        - Known Artists., 31 (Box 53)
          - Miscellaneous Artists., 13 (Box 53)
            - Ben Tre, Howard., 1 (Box 53)
            - Chihuly, Dale, 1941-., 2 (Box 53)
            - Frankl, P. T., 1 (Box 53)
            - Hutter, Sidney., 1 (Box 53)
            - Labino, Dominick., 1 (Box 53)
            - Pollard, Don., 1 (Box 53)
            - Steuben Glass., 2 (Box 53)
            - Teague, Walter D., 1 (Box 53)
            - Waugh, Sidney., 2 (Box 53)
            - Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1867-1959., 1 (Box 53)
          - Individual Artists., 18 (Box 53)
            - Tiffany, Louis Comfort, 1848-1933, and studio., 18 (Box 53)
- Industrial Design. (Box 54)
  - Unknown designer., 9 (Box 54)
  - Known designers., 8 (Box 54)
  - Albers, Josef., 1 (Box 54)
  - Clark, Paul, and Gemmill, Anthony, XX C., 1 (Box 54)
  - Franklin, Benjamin, XVIII C., 1 (Box 54)
  - Morris, I.P., XIX C.., 1 (Box 54)
  - Pfisterer, XX C., 1 (Box 54)
  - Wheeler and Wilson Mfg. Co., XIX C., 1 (Box 54)
  - Wurlitzer, XX C., 1 (Box 54)
- Intarsia. (Box 54)
  - Roman., 2 (Box 54)
  - Italian., 32 (Box 54)
    - Unknown Artists., 6 (Box 54)
    - Known Artists., 24 (Box 54)
      - Bartolommeo da Pola, Renaissance., 1 (Box 54)
      - Damiano da Bergamo, Fra, Renaissance., 2 (Box 54)
      - Francesco di Giorgio, attributed to, XV C., 13 (Box 54)
      - Giovanni da Verona, 1457-1525., 4 (Box 54)
      - Lendinari, C., XV C., 1 (Box 54)
      - Pontelli, Baccio, 1450-1492., 1 (Box 54)
      - Vignola, Jacopo, 1507-1573., 1 (Box 54)
      - Vincenzo delle Vacche, active 1520-1523., 1 (Box 54)
- Ivories. (Box 55)
  - Miscellaneous works., 3 (Box 55)
  - Islamic., 7 (Box 55)
  - Ancient World., 6 (Box 55)
  - Early Medieval., 276 (Box 55)
    - Miscellaneous works., 12 (Box 55)
    - IV Century., 18 (Box 55)
    - V Century., 34 (Box 56)
    - VI Century., 77 (Box 57)
      - Miscellaneous works., 51 (Box 57)
      - Throne of Maximianus., 26 (Box 57)
    - VIII Century., 24 (Box 58)
      - Franks Casket., 24 (Box 58)
    - IX Century., 7 (Box 58)
    - X Century., 43 (Box 58)
    - XI Century., 38 (Box 59)
    - XII Century., 23 (Box 59)
  - Carolingian., 39 (Box 60)
  - Romanesque to Modern., 105 (Box 60)
    - Miscellaneous works., 4 (Box 60)
      - Unknown Artists., 3 (Box 60)
      - Known Artists., 1 (Box 60)
        - Berg, Magnus Eliesen, 1666-1739., 1 (Box 60)
    - Britain., 17 (Box 60)
    - Denmark., 2 (Box 60)
    - Flanders., 2 (Box 60)
    - France., 40 (Box 61)
      - Miscellaneous works., 5 (Box 61)
      - XIII Century., 8 (Box 61)
      - XIV Century., 29 (Box 61)
      - XV to XVI Century., 7 (Box 61)
      - XVII to XX Century., 1 (Box 61)
    - Germany., 20 (Box 62)
      - Unknown Artists., 18 (Box 62)
      - Known artists., 2 (Box 62)
        - Deutschmann, Joseph, 1717-1787., 1 (Box 62)
        - Master of the Furies, XVII C., 1 (Box 62)